[
    {
        "question": "Þa cwæð God nis na gedafenlic þæt #### man ana beo - Then God said 'it is not fitting that this man be alone'",
        "correctAnswer": "þes|ðes",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular masculine nominative 'man' so it stays as 'þes'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þa gefæstnode he #### ræd wið þæt werod þe he bewiste, and hi ealle to ðam ræde gebugon - Then he confirmed this resolve with the host over which he ruled, and they all bowed to that resolve",
        "correctAnswer": "þisne|ðisne",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular masculine accusative 'ræd' so it becomes 'þisne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ac se wurðmynt wæs #### dæges mærðe gehealden, þæt hie mid heofenlicum leohte hie geswutelodon - But that honour was reserved for the greatness of this day, that they should manifest themselves with heavenly light",
        "correctAnswer": "þisses",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular masculine genitive 'dæg' so it becomes 'þisses'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On Godes naman ahreose #### templ mid eallum þam deofolgyldum þe him on eardiað - In the name of God, let this temple fall with all the idols that dwell within it",
        "correctAnswer": "þis",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular neuter nominative 'templ' so it becomes 'þis'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nim #### cild mid þære meder and fleoh to Egypta lande - Take this child with the mother and flee to Egypt",
        "correctAnswer": "þis",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular neuter accusative 'cild' so it becomes 'þis'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Adam þa wæs wunigende on #### life mid geswince, and he and his wif ða bearn gestryndon - Adam then was continuing in this life with toil, and he and his wife begat children",
        "correctAnswer": "þissum",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular neuter dative 'life' so it becomes 'þissum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Widewe wæs #### Anna, þe we gefyrn ær embe spræcon - This Anna was a widow who we have spoken of before",
        "correctAnswer": "þeos",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular feminine nominative 'Anna' so it becomes 'þeos'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "þas",
                "explanation": "Though the word order is confusing, Anna is the subject, not the object of 'wæs' so it takes the singular nominative feminine 'þeos'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Send me þinne engel on fyrenum wolcne þæt þa embgange ealle #### ceastre þæt ne magen geneosian for þsem fyre - Send me your angel from heaven in a fiery cloud that he my encompass all this city",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular feminine accusative 'ceaster' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Þæt sædon gehwilce wise lareowas þæt hie habbað gefremod heora ærist to ðam ecan lífe swa swa we ealle don sceolon on ende #### worulde -  All wise teachers have said that they have effected their resurrection to eternal life, as we all shall do at the end of this world",
        "correctAnswer": "þisre",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular feminine genitive 'worulde' so it becomes 'þisre'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Oft ys seo halige þrinnys geswutelod on #### boc - Often is the holy trinity revealed in this book",
        "correctAnswer": "þisre",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the singular feminine dative 'boc' so it becomes 'þisre'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "#### ðing we ne magon don butan earfoðnyssum - These things we cannot do without difficulty",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural neuter nominative 'ðing' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Nimað þis gold ond #### gymstanas ond farað ond bicgað eow landare - Take this gold and these gemstones and go and buy yourself land",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural neuter accusative 'gymstan' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "#### læssan giefa þæt sind þa fugelas þe wæron wannspedigra manna giefa wæron for Criste geoffrode - These smaller gifts, that is the birds which were the gifts of indigent persons, were offered for Christ",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural feminine nominative 'giefu' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On ðære ealdan æ is gehwær gesett, þæt God het gelomlice #### fugelas offrian on his lace - In the old law it is in several places mentioned, that God frequently commanded these birds to be offered to him in sacrifice",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural masculine accusative 'fugel' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Eala hu rihtlice hie andetton þone halgan geleafan mid #### wordum: On frymðe wæs word, and þæt word wæs mid Gode - O how rightly they acknowledged the holy faith with these words, 'In the beginning was the word, and the word was with God'",
        "correctAnswer": "þissum",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural neuter dative 'word' so it becomes 'þissum'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Gif ðu Godes Sunu sy wend #### stanas to hlafum ond et - If you are the son of god, turn these stones to loaves and eat",
        "correctAnswer": "þas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þes' is modifying the plural masculine accusative 'gymstan' so it becomes 'þas'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]